[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a167", "question": "Who played Sarah Conner in the 1991 film \"Terminator 2: Judgment Day\"?", "answer": "Linda Hamilton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133887c", "question": "Who painted Self Portrait with Bandaged Ear?", "answer": "Vincent Van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c016", "question": "What did American Harland David Sanders give to the world in the 1930s?", "answer": "Kentucky Fried Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd39", "question": "What trade name comes from combining the French words for velvet and hook?", "answer": "Velcro", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f84", "question": "The Michael Douglas film \"A Perfect Murder\" is a remake of what 1950s thriller?", "answer": "Dial M for Murder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b834", "question": "How many times are Mexican refried beans fried?", "answer": "Once", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba4d8874c93a3298b2149", "question": "What is the Welsh name for Mount Snowdon?", "answer": "Yr Wyddfa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf5c", "question": "What was given to children to rid them of threadworm?", "answer": "Salt enema", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990b018b72eedf883a8c70f", "question": "In what country do people speak the language they call Nihongo?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cdd", "question": "What sci-fi movie featured David Bowie and Rip Torn?", "answer": "The Man Who Fell to Earth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597ddf0577980686f722d181", "question": "What year was the first official soccer game played?", "answer": "1863", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c636", "question": "Which two features are longer on a hare than a rabbit?", "answer": "Legs and Ears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a435", "question": "In what country is the Great Sandy Desert located?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a1", "question": "Who Had A Hit In 1993 With \"She Don't Let Nobody\"?", "answer": "Chaka Demus & Pliers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b3fce662d71a53650fe7", "question": "Which European town inspired Vincent van Gogh's famous \u201cStarry Night\u201d?", "answer": "Saint-R\u00e9my-de-Provence, France", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c74e", "question": "What plant is the most common cause of hay fever?", "answer": "Ragweed", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945d", "question": "Which actor was the voice of Charles Muntz in the 2009 movie \"Up\"?", "answer": "Christopher Plummer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae866037f28483af1e7fdd2", "question": "What is the name of the band whose songs \"All Star\" and \"I\u2019m a Believer\" were featured in the 2001 film \"Shrek\"?", "answer": "Smash Mouth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a728c8f6bcd28c119383289", "question": "What is the first event in a Men's Heptathalon?", "answer": "60 Metres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e2", "question": "Which actress turned singer released an album in 2009 entitled \"Come To Life\"?", "answer": "Natalie Imbruglia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133982f", "question": "What war was the setting of the TV show \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Korean War", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd666faa5bfecdd737e0869", "question": "What is the busiest time of the year for air travel in the U.S.?", "answer": "Thanksgiving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9b753364247bf200fb871", "question": "Which chemical element has the atomic number of 1?", "answer": "Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600245024be4723ccac221ab", "question": "In Leonardo da Vinci's Annunciation, who is depicted with the virgin Mary?", "answer": "Gabriel -- The angel is sent by God to tell the virgin Mary that she will miraculously conceive and give birth to a son, Jesus.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b599", "question": "Which artist's song was the 10 billionth iTunes download?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e6", "question": "What is the official name of the Michelin Man?", "answer": "Bibendum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3c6344f0f6af5b066630", "question": "Nuclear membrane, cytoplasm, and nucleus are parts of a what?", "answer": "Cell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3cb", "question": "What beer shares its name with the river that runs through Amsterdam?", "answer": "Amstel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab1b2544fda37788a9a1db8", "question": "What is the capital of Burkina Faso?", "answer": "Ouagadougou", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067f21ff9c0647b50a8081", "question": "How many gold medals did US swimmer Michael Phelps win at the 2016 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "5", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4bf", "question": "In medicine, what does the abbreviation LASIK stand for?", "answer": "Laser-Assisted In Situ Keratomileusis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c815", "question": "What Italian physician was the first to describe the way the ovaries connect to the uterus in humans?", "answer": "Gabriele Falloppio", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac65", "question": "What name was Eva Peron known by?", "answer": "Evita", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bceb", "question": "Cap'n Crunch's flagship is named for what fish?", "answer": "The guppy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b174425bb2d29f81593b6f8", "question": "Where was George A. Custer defeated?", "answer": "At the Battle of the Little Bighorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a410", "question": "Which US state is sometimes referred to as the Beaver State?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c2", "question": "What animal lives in a \"drey\"?", "answer": "The squirrel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe52d2c1bf59ab7d2e3810c", "question": "What is a grouping of bananas called?", "answer": "A hand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b0", "question": "What female spy was arrested and sentenced to death in France in 1917 for spying on behalf of the Germans?", "answer": "Mata Hari", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339094", "question": "What is the name of Hades' three-headed guard dog?", "answer": "Cerberus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e5", "question": "What year was actor W. C. Fields born?", "answer": "1880", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfff", "question": "Who is known as \"Big Mama\" in ladies pro golf?", "answer": "JoAnne Carner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339000", "question": "Who was the Egyptian god of the Afterlife?", "answer": "Osiris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe3f12d8b5801b8f54a7fbe", "question": "Which famous figures are featured on Prague\u2019s astronomical clock?", "answer": "The 12 Apostles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c78b", "question": "How many oxygen atoms does a molecule of ozone have?", "answer": "3", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b32341abf195a31e15d73a2", "question": "What desert covers most of southern Mongolia?", "answer": "The Gobi desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015fbdafe83fe1f2a824c3d", "question": "In the latter 19th century, which now-common Valentine's Day practice was considered bad luck?", "answer": "Signing Valentine's cards -- Reportedly, some people still refuse to sign Valentines Day cards using their own name.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e10", "question": "What British comedian refers to himself as an \"executive transvestite\"?", "answer": "Eddie Izzard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c06a", "question": "Which Major League pitcher accumulated the most victories from 2000-09?", "answer": "Andy Pettitte", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f9", "question": "In the movie \"Stand By Me\", what did Gordy, Chris, Vern and Teddy set out to find?", "answer": "A Body", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66145a5bfecdd737e083a", "question": "What is the longest recorded case of the hiccups in history?", "answer": "68 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c3e9930ebfabb9c85d8a970", "question": "What film starred Rosie O'Donnell, Rita Wilson and Meg Ryan?", "answer": "Sleepless in Seattle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b0f", "question": "Who won her first Best Actress Oscar for the movie \"Sophie's Choice\"?", "answer": "Meryl Streep", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f93efe83fe1f2a824c31", "question": "Who created the first electrically lit Christmas tree?", "answer": "Edward H. Johnson was an American inventor best known for creating the first electrically illuminated Christmas tree in 1882", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fde4f72c6c6b019850c9a8a", "question": "Who is credited with being the first Pharaoh of Egypt?", "answer": "Menes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe93d396bd93ce3a4e5f6b1", "question": "Which type of chemical bond is strongest?", "answer": "Ionic bond", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe73433eec85e375820b230", "question": "Who was the overall commander of the Pacific Fleet during World War II?", "answer": "Admiral Chester Nimitz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd969c023c87fd04dd15e0c", "question": "What was the first major battle fought only in the air?", "answer": "Battle of Britain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f6e77a9e54d890926f6c5", "question": "What Caribbean record does the Dominican Republic hold?", "answer": "Highest mountain peak - The highest peak in the Caribbean, Pico Duarte, soars 10,417 feet above the trees.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f7", "question": "What gender are whiptail lizards?", "answer": "Female", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aecd", "question": "What US general accepted the surrender of Japan?", "answer": "General Douglas MacArthur", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c90cfc152800b05cac20f0b", "question": "What is the only African nation with Spanish as the official language?", "answer": "Equatorial Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5a0", "question": "What do the letters LG stand for in the name of the international electronics and chemical brand LG?", "answer": "Lucky-Goldstar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f61901dd7bf43be5e82f", "question": "What does the W at the start of a radio station's call sign typically indicate?", "answer": "East of the Mississippi River", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba8c", "question": "How much does it cost to purchase Boardwalk in the standard game of Monopoly?", "answer": "$400", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51195ff04d658268c92c7", "question": "Who was the first Republican Vice President of the United States?", "answer": "Hannibal Hamlin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba48", "question": "What US city hosts the world's largest hot air balloon festival?", "answer": "Albuquerque", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e8a8b02404ad935a7e1a644", "question": "What is the BTS Variety Show called on their V-LIVE channel?", "answer": "Run BTS", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339361", "question": "What occupation did Mary Richards have on \"The Mary Tyler Moore Show\"?", "answer": "Assistant producer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b62", "question": "What broadcast television network debuted on October 9, 1986?", "answer": "FOX", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a446", "question": "What mountain overlooks Cape Town, South Africa?", "answer": "Table Mountain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339832", "question": "The life of what jazz legend was portrayed in the 1988 film \"Bird\"?", "answer": "Charlie Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea7", "question": "What was the surname of Nicholas II, the last tsar of Russia?", "answer": "Romanov", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3af", "question": "Which world champion was beaten by a machine called Deep Blue in 1997?\u00a0", "answer": "Gary Kasparov", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339096", "question": "Who were the siblings of the Greek god Hera?", "answer": "Poseidon, Zeus, Hades, Demeter, Hestia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015eabbfe83fe1f2a824bf3", "question": "What does the color red represent in the American flag?", "answer": "Red symbolizes hardiness and valor.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdffbdd1cf6db9ac4808cf9", "question": "What is the only country capital that contains a national park?", "answer": "Nairobi, Kenya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe379ec0ada16518afdc056", "question": "In what year did the final member of the Imperial Japanese Army surrender?", "answer": "1974", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5eb73d335e259d7869087333", "question": "What is the name of the legendary racetrack that hosts the Kentucky Derby?", "answer": "Churchill Downs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac7d", "question": "Who was president when the agency that would become the FBI was created?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5a", "question": "What was the name of the town where all the characters lived in the comic strip \u201cL\u2019il Abner\u201d?", "answer": "Dogpatch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abd2", "question": "What is the capital of Bermuda?", "answer": "Hamilton", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6008e07df4f3bc4a292f8632", "question": "Who said \"The journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step\"?", "answer": "Lao Tzu (The Chinese philosopher's quote about great things having humble beginnings comes from his famous work, \"Tao Te Ching\".)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b583e662d71a53650ffb", "question": "In which classic children's book does the protagonist only eat cabbage?", "answer": "\"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff7c11b2b316f4693fb679b", "question": "What is the space between windows called?", "answer": "Interfenestration", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4dd", "question": "What fruit comes in Key and Kaffir variety?", "answer": "Limes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5902a0f0cad1ec93f27df772", "question": "What do you ferment to make kombucha?", "answer": "Sweetened tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c88e6b222f44c2d77a29c42", "question": "Who wrote both \"Anna Karenina\" and \"War and Peace\"?", "answer": "Leo Tolstoy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dbb", "question": "What novelist of westerns went by his middle name, since his first was Pearl?", "answer": "Zane Grey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e48", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"The Naked Gun\"?", "answer": "O. J. Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e96127ccba3ffe45786e8", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Arachne challenge to a weaving contest?", "answer": "Athena", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a979", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Eduskunta?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aef4", "question": "Which Roman emperor died after eating poisoned mushrooms given to him by his wife Agrippina?", "answer": "Claudius", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febd3747e83c707845b2153", "question": "What is the name of the prequel to \"The Silence of the Lambs\"?", "answer": "\"Red Dragon\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a878", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"Carnaby Street\"?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b00e", "question": "What was Lyndon B. Johnson's middle name?", "answer": "Baines", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5adc6ce05a3942286e0e", "question": "Which team did John Madden, of \"Madden NFL\" fame, win a Super Bowl with as head coach?", "answer": "Oakland Raiders", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f55", "question": "What is the name of Woody's horse in the movie franchise \"Toy Story\"?", "answer": "Bullseye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945f", "question": "How does Jack die in the movie \"The Shining\"?", "answer": "He freezes to death", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b100", "question": "What President's Vice-Presidents were Aaron Burr and George Clinton, respectively?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60121a0263c99d48cd169aff", "question": "What kind of nut is used to make marzipan?", "answer": "Almond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c5", "question": "Who produced two booklets for \"Comic Relief\" under the names Newt Scamander and Kennilworthy Whisp?", "answer": "J.K. Rowling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8de", "question": "What animals teeth were used as knife blades by Natives?", "answer": "Beaver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917c", "question": "What is the name of the actor who plays Dexter Morgan on the TV show \"Dexter\"?", "answer": "Michael C. Hall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c1", "question": "Who played Marshal Matt Dillon on the TV series \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "James Arness", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339646", "question": "Which of the four Beatles was the eldest?", "answer": "Ringo Starr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae87", "question": "What did the US government purchase from Spain in 1819?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5906835cff9c0647b50a80a6", "question": "Alec Baldwin started hosting which ABC show on June 26, 2016?", "answer": "Match Game", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa82", "question": "In which large bay would you find the Belcher Islands?", "answer": "Hudson Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feddffd6ce05a3942286db5", "question": "Which American sitcom once aired an episode entitled \"April Fool's Day\" which was actually about Tax Day?", "answer": "\"Roseanne\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523d84736d4be723796b43", "question": "For what period of time is the Governor General of Canada appointed?", "answer": "Unfixed", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339589", "question": "What movie includes the quote \"Your heart is free. Have the courage to follow it\"?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4dc", "question": "What two alcoholic ingredients is the traditional Martini cocktail made of?", "answer": "Gin and vermouth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b830", "question": "What is the device that measures the number of steps you take when walking or running?", "answer": "Pedometer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae0", "question": "What classic movie was based on a book titled \"Everyone Comes to Rick's\"?", "answer": "Casablanca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901dc7b709c1c34536e6eb6", "question": "Who is the target of the Terminator in the original 1984 movie of the same name?", "answer": "Sarah Connor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59068295ff9c0647b50a809e", "question": "On what streaming platform was Kanye West\u2019s \"The Life of Pablo\" album launched?", "answer": "Tidal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eaa", "question": "What screen legend made her final appearance in the movie \"High Society\"?", "answer": "Grace Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133970f", "question": "In which decade did John Travolta star in \"Grease\"?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb89d7e83c707845b2134", "question": "Who said, \"History will be kind to me for I intend to write it\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba65", "question": "In what year were Sea-\u00adMonkeys first marketed?", "answer": "1957", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b29", "question": "What Hanna-Barbera cartoon character was always causing trouble for Ranger Smith?", "answer": "Yogi Bear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60160011fe83fe1f2a824c52", "question": "Who is officially the patron saint of May Day?", "answer": "Saint Joseph, the husband of the Virgin Mary, was made the patron saint of May Day in 1955 due to his perceived work ethic.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e8a806d333868d34d74c", "question": "Where can you find Pont Du Gard, part of an ancient Roman aqueduct?", "answer": "N\u00eemes, France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd968ac23c87fd04dd15e02", "question": "Which US military awards were established during the Civil War?", "answer": "The Navy and Marine Corps Medal of Honor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339962", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what nickname did Milhouse give himself?", "answer": "Thrillhouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b915", "question": "What breakfast favorite, with a hole in the middle, is equal to 4 slices of bread?", "answer": "A bagel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae2", "question": "Which British prime minister was awarded the Nobel Prize for Literature?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339047", "question": "In Greek mythology, what city did Cadmus found and rule?", "answer": "Thebes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f74cfa9e54d890926f700", "question": "What is banned in public places in Florida after 6 pm on a Thursday?", "answer": "Flatulence (farting)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee5", "question": "The first Tonka truck was made in what year?", "answer": "1947", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b323740bf195a31e15d73c3", "question": "Lisbon lies on which river?", "answer": "Tagus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133916d", "question": "Who created the animated TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Trey Parker and Matt Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a4fe20565ad31a57c7c5", "question": "Who was the first sitting US President to throw the first pitch on Opening Day?", "answer": "William Howard Taft", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad3d", "question": "Which archaeologist discovered King Tut's tomb in 1922?", "answer": "Howard Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339481", "question": "What was David Dunn's weakness in the movie \"Unbreakable\"?", "answer": "Water", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81dbed0de9af39e9d4692", "question": "Who was the first woman appointed to a president's cabinet?", "answer": "Frances Perkins", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf0", "question": "What popular actor won Western Australia's junior chess championship at age 10?", "answer": "Heath Ledger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66d3aa5bfecdd737e089d", "question": "What is the total face point value of all the tiles in Scrabble?", "answer": "187", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af25bdfb63e5727cf5a485d", "question": "What year did Cher release the single \"Believe\"?", "answer": "1999", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3234debf195a31e15d73a9", "question": "Who played Derek Flint in the 1966 film \"Our Man Flint\"?", "answer": "James Coburn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921c", "question": "What city did the band U2 form in?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a162c85f01ec323f8491730", "question": "The song \"Matchmaker, Matchmaker\" came from which musical?", "answer": "Fiddler on the Roof", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c7b", "question": "What actor is synonymous with the Indiana Jones character?", "answer": "Harrison Ford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7dc8ff048f679a45abfe", "question": "Androphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Men", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958b", "question": "Who plays the role of Sarah Jordan in the 2005 movie \"The Island\"?", "answer": "Scarlett Johansson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b571b7067df192a942e3369", "question": "Managua is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Nicaragua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e32", "question": "Who is Joely Richardson's mother?", "answer": "Vanessa Redgrave", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b398", "question": "Who founded the American Red Cross?", "answer": "Clara Barton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c76d0775fa611bce67d9", "question": "Which organization publishes \"Boys\u2019 Life\" magazine?", "answer": "Boy Scouts of America", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b681", "question": "Which airline absorbed the carrier \"People Express\" in 1987?", "answer": "Continental", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caae", "question": "What do zoologists call the leader of a wolf pack?", "answer": "The alpha male", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a7c220565ad31a57c7ee", "question": "Where was paper first produced?", "answer": "China", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f0b0ff048f679a45aaa3", "question": "Sociophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Social evaluation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010c7940775fa611bce67db", "question": "How long is a tiger's tooth (canine teeth)?", "answer": "3 inches long", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600241334be4723ccac22172", "question": "A painting by what artist was once mistakenly hung upside-down at MoMA?", "answer": "Henri Matisse -- A stock broker, familiar with Matisse's work, noticed \u201cLe Bateau\u201d was hanging upside down at the museum in NYC.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6002413e4be4723ccac22173", "question": "Sydney Carton is the central character in what Charles Dickens novel?", "answer": "\"A Tale of Two Cities\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c47e", "question": "In which country are you most likely to see southern crowned pigeons and flame bowerbirds?", "answer": "Papua New Guinea", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbe606ce05a3942286eee", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Everybody Wants to Rule the World\"?", "answer": "Tears For Fears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338880", "question": "What is the last word in the Bible?", "answer": "Amen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60136faa1381754895396379", "question": "In 2000, what character was elected U.S. President in the DC universe?", "answer": "Lex Luthor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c633", "question": "What are the twin stars in the constellation of Gemini called?", "answer": "Pollux and Castor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febb4997e83c707845b211a", "question": "What color is eigengrau?", "answer": "Dark gray", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f1", "question": "What can you figure out about the weather by counting the cricket chirps?", "answer": "Temperature", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab34", "question": "Off what country lies the island of Zanzibar?", "answer": "Tanzania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e99e2ebfabb9c85d8a976", "question": "Berlin stands on the banks of which river?", "answer": "Spree", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd20", "question": "In the famous logo, what is the Morton Salt girl holding in her right hand?", "answer": "An umbrella", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff141d3b0ee8c595b6d39a7", "question": "What artist is famous for the \"Helga Pictures\"?", "answer": "Andrew Wyeth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339154", "question": "In \"The Saint\" series of books, what is Inspector Teal's full name?", "answer": "Claud Eustace Teal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339662", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Krusty's monkey?", "answer": "Mr. Teeny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe36cff0ada16518afdc03f", "question": "What car company advertised \"Drivers wanted\"?", "answer": "Volkswagen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b473", "question": "What duo first published the \"Michelin Guide\" in 1900?", "answer": "Andre and Edouard Michelin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c41f", "question": "How many eyelids does a cat have on each eye?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a632", "question": "The Niagara Falls empties in which Great Lake?", "answer": "Lake Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0ae5ee662d71a53650fb9", "question": "A poorly supported yet persistent rumour has it that Denmark\u2019s King Christian VIII, not a shoemaker, was whose father?", "answer": "Hans Christian Andersen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb3", "question": "What slogan is painted on the nose of Robert Duvall's Wagner-blasting helicopter in \"Apocalypse Now\"?", "answer": "Death from above", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a06b", "question": "In which film did Donna Summer make her debut as an aspiring disco singer?", "answer": "Thank God It's Friday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ce", "question": "Which actress played a character named Ellen Ripley in the movie \"Alien\"?", "answer": "Sigourney Weaver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b80c", "question": "What sport has a hooker in a scrum?", "answer": "Rugby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d4", "question": "On the ph scale, what number indicates neutrality?", "answer": "7", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63a", "question": "Which bird lays the largest eggs?", "answer": "Ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7bf10877e98cb97778965", "question": "What is the smallest country in South America?", "answer": "Suriname", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d46f9af8e329de4f877888", "question": "Liza Minelli played what character in the 1972 film \"Cabaret\"?", "answer": "Sally Bowles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c988", "question": "What is the name given to a group of geese?", "answer": "Gaggle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1d3", "question": "Which US soul singer was known as \"Lady Day\"?", "answer": "Billie Holiday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c36e", "question": "What is at an average distance of 238,857 miles from the Earth?", "answer": "The Moon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ce", "question": "What Ivy League school is located in Massachusetts?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388be", "question": "What food of the three bears did Goldilocks eat?", "answer": "Porridge", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb83", "question": "What citrus beverage has used the ad slogan \"Open a Bottle of Sunshine\"?", "answer": "Sunny Delight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c009", "question": "In pool, what color is the eight ball?", "answer": "Black", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af25916b63e5727cf5a484b", "question": "What year did The Outhere Brothers release the song \"Boom Boom Boom\"?", "answer": "1995", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cc45bb53d1af658864df", "question": "How many years after the founding of the company did Hallmark release its first Christmas cards?", "answer": "5 years", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339675", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what color is the tablecloth in the Simpsons' kitchen?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c9e7877e98cb977789fe", "question": "In Oaxaca, Mexico, Christmas Eve is also called \"Night of\" what vegetable?", "answer": "Radish", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59cdb37765ff7d326b622a7f", "question": "\"From a Distance\" was a hit in the early 1990s for which singer?", "answer": "Bette Midler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1aa", "question": "What Elvis Presley film is set in England?", "answer": "Double Trouble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eca", "question": "What Sonic Youth LP did \"Entertainment Weekly\" call the best album of 1992?", "answer": "Dirty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f27", "question": "\"The Great Rock 'n' Roll Swindle\" is a mockumentary about what band?", "answer": "The Sex Pistols", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c4", "question": "Who wrote the 1897 horror novel \"Dracula\"?", "answer": "Bram Stoker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a3", "question": "\"Coulrophobia\" is the fear of what?", "answer": "Clowns", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc64", "question": "How many different car models were there in the first Hot Wheels release in 1968?", "answer": "16", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfdffddb668d7dfe168b5bc", "question": "Chablis wine comes from which French wine region?", "answer": "Burgundy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a5", "question": "Which Flintstones character was absent from the Flintstone vitamins until 1996?", "answer": "Betty Rubble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391de", "question": "Who played Mr. Blonde in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Michael Madsen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989adbccb8751d53e7d7611", "question": "Which Roman Emperor received the title \"Gothicus Maximus\" because of his campaign against the Goths and the Heruli?", "answer": "Tacitus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81fc7d0de9af39e9d4699", "question": "What virtue do the red stripes on the American flag stand for?", "answer": "Valor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c7", "question": "What is the Latin name for a guinea pig?", "answer": "Caviaprocellus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7692ceec85e375820b2ad", "question": "What is the Welsh name for Wales?", "answer": "Cymru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339405", "question": "Who narrated the 2007 movie \"Enchanted\"?", "answer": "Julie Andrews", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f73", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Caractacus Potts?", "answer": "Chitty Chitty Bang Bang", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a62302ebb971c1417fb8d", "question": "Which French district does Claret come from?", "answer": "Bordeaux", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69b0f20565ad31a57c75b", "question": "In Nazi concentration camps, a pink triangle signified the prisoner as what?", "answer": "Homosexual", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b3", "question": "The Linke Scale is used to measure the blueness of what?", "answer": "The sky", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990af76b72eedf883a8c707", "question": "Which US state was nicknamed \"Old Dominion\"?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af258c7b63e5727cf5a4848", "question": "Who co-produced the song \"Summertime\" with Will Smith?", "answer": "DJ Jazzy Jeff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b58a06d333868d34d6e9", "question": "In the U.S., what famous slogan first appeared on World War I recruiting posters?", "answer": "\"I want you\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af7c", "question": "The Battle of Lexington occurred at the start of what war?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133999b", "question": "What sex were the collies playing Lassie in the 1940's, 50's and 60's?", "answer": "Male", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a86a", "question": "Which Bay is located to the north of Spain?", "answer": "Bay of Biscay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339090", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was the god of the underworld?", "answer": "Hades", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4b39f06d333868d34d6da", "question": "Who did Churchill call the \"American Carnot\" in World War II?", "answer": "General George Marshall", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ded35dea2747c8aff16d47", "question": "Which British rock group released a 1990s album called \"Parklife\"?", "answer": "Blur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133997f", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Krusty the Clown's helper monkey?", "answer": "Mr. Teeny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b85", "question": "What\u2019s the ballet term for a 360 degree turn on one foot?", "answer": "A Pirouette", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac59", "question": "What year did the red maple leaf design officially become Canada's flag?", "answer": "1965", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b7ff8fc3a3a814d89068c50", "question": "What is the full name of the Shakespearean tragedy \"Hamlet\"?", "answer": "The Tragedy of Hamlet, Prince of Denmark", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc8a0ec223966ae8f8891", "question": "Pro golfers rack up points as they compete for what corporate-sponsored cup that was first awarded in 2007?", "answer": "The FedEx Cup", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe7", "question": "How many players are in a Polo team?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acfd", "question": "What is widely considered to be man's first celestial observatory?", "answer": "Stonehenge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e3f4ae5cb9e8bda6821369", "question": "Approximatly when did construction of the Colosseum finish?", "answer": "80 AD", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefc3ae6ce05a3942286f26", "question": "John Paul Jones was the bassist and keyboardist for what rock band?", "answer": "Led Zeppelin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9e139e748bb36357acdf4", "question": "What is the reality TV show based on the Robertson Family?", "answer": "Duck Dynasty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9088901dd7bf43be5e885", "question": "What color is on the outside arc of a rainbow?", "answer": "Red", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c353", "question": "Mn is the chemical symbol for which element?", "answer": "Manganese", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389ed", "question": "Who reputedly told a customs officer: \"I have nothing to declare except my genius\"?", "answer": "Oscar Wilde", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf80", "question": "What is a tightrope walker called?", "answer": "Funambulist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd9733823c87fd04dd15e57", "question": "How many states were in the original US Confederacy?", "answer": "7", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fbaea1a0738315b1fb74e2a", "question": "Phlebitis is the inflimation of what?", "answer": "A vein", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a0", "question": "In what time zone is Oklahoma located?", "answer": "Central Time Zone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d1180d4fea7fe947a22280", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for lead?", "answer": "Pb", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a34c", "question": "What is the world's widest river?", "answer": "The Amazon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339791", "question": "What KISS star sported the longest tongue in rock?", "answer": "Gene Simmons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399d9", "question": "What was the name of Dr. Evil\u2019s cat in the \"Austin Powers\" movies series?", "answer": "Mr. Bigglesworth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad25", "question": "The Iran hostages were released in January 1981 after 444 days of captivity; what was their first stop?", "answer": "Algiers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e4", "question": "Which popular musician co-wrote the song \"I'm afraid of Americans\" with David Bowie?", "answer": "Brian Eno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a732", "question": "What river flows along the western border of Illinois?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe37a010ada16518afdc057", "question": "What mascot represented the women who went to work in factories to help with the war effort during World War II?", "answer": "Rosie the Riveter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133add7", "question": "When did the \"Eighty Years War\" start?", "answer": "1568", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea419eff048f679a45ab6f", "question": "Which part of an elephant's body has the most muscles?", "answer": "The trunk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6008d9b9f4f3bc4a292f8611", "question": "When did the Mayflower reach America?", "answer": "The Mayflower landed along the shores of Cape Cod on November 11, 1620.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e5", "question": "The Caribbean island of Aruba is part of what European kingdom?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339442", "question": "Who played the role of Hana in the movie \"The English Patient\"?", "answer": "Juliette Binoche", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cace", "question": "What is heliology the study of?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5fba6ce05a3942286e46", "question": "What famous musician was nicknamed Mr. Showmanship?", "answer": "Liberace", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c88e98222f44c2d77a29c48", "question": "Marilyn Monroe made her first movie appearance in 1947 in which film?", "answer": "Dangerous Years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a82e", "question": "Pashto is the official language of which country?", "answer": "Afghanistan", "category": "geography"}]